CHAHAT SHRIVASTAVA

FRONT-END DEVELOPER

CONTACT

- +919111723595, +918839336485
- chahatshrivastava2306@gmail.com
- in www.linkedin.com/in/chahat
- https://github.com/Chahat-23

PROFILE SUMMARY

A dynamic Front-End Developer with over 2 years of experience creating intuitive user interfaces using React.js. I build and fine-tune interfaces and address defects for enhanced user experience. My background in various types of content creation adds a creative edge. With a solid foundation in HTML, CSS, and Js from my early days, I blend technical skills with creative flair to deliver standout digital solutions.

EDUCATION

July 2018 - May 2022 CHANDIGARH UNIVERSITY

BTech, CSE - 7.8 CGPA

April 2015 - March 2018 BAL BHARATI PUBLIC SCHOOL

- 12th 8.5 CGPA
- 10th 9.8 CGPA

SKILLS

- React.js
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript
- Git
- Bootstrap, Material UI, Tailwind CSS
- Linux/ UNIX
- Defect & Vulnerability Management
- Quality Assurance
- Research & Analysis
- Content Strategy and Creation, SEO
- Creative Designing & Social Media
- Communication & interpersonal skills
- Social media marketing & strategizing

WORK EXPERIENCE

Standard Chartered GBS

JULY 2022 - PRESENT

Front End Developer

- Working on internal supervisory dashboard, since Sept 2023, implemented 20% components, including CRUD grids, forms, navigations, etc.
- Began initially with code migration of the existing dashboard from old version in Ember.Js to React.Js
- Worked on Jest unit test cases, taking up coverage to 40% over-all
- My current 50% of capacity goes into next version UI/UX updates with React.Js and Material UI
- Simultaneously, 50% of my capacity goes to handling vulnerabilities fixes
- Before this, was a part of Quality Assurance team; Worked on SQL, Unix & aided with manual testing & creating feature files for 75% of new projects

Abstinent Research & Technologies

JUNE 2019 - AUGUST 2019

Intern Web Designer

- Designed and developed 2 websites, replicating the Manorama news portal and the State Bank of India's site respectively
- Gained hands-on experience in HTML, CSS, & Bootstrap, handling 100% UI development for the above
- Contributed to creating visually engaging and responsive web interfaces

Freelance Content Writer

MAY 2020 - AUGUST 2023

- Produced SEO-compliant content for PlutoPe, Kometverse, The Dapp List, GameAppStudio, Monetas Global, AASN Digital Hawk, and BOP Consultancy over the period of over 3 years with several freelance gigs
- Created 100+ tweets, 500+ blogs, 50+ newsletters, PRs, technical docs, etc
- Gathered & analyzed requirements, conducted research, collaborated with graphic designers & aligned weekly deliverables with those requirements

PORTFOLIO

https://profile-portfolio-chahat-23s-projects.vercel.app/

LANGUAGES

- English
- Hindi

ACHIEVEMENTS

- State Level International Mathematics Olympiad 2017
- Top performer Soft Skills in Graduation 2nd Year
- 1st Position Epsilon 2k19 presentation competition
- NSS Camp 2019 Participant
- Content Writer & Strategizer for Startups (Web2 & Web3) 2020 to 2023